Can you help me pick
an engagement ring?
약혼반지 고르는 것 좀 도와줘
난 도저히 결정을 못하겠어
I can't figure this out. Should I get her a
Tiffany cut or a princess cut or a..?
보자, '티파니 컷'으로 할까
'프린세스 컷'으로 할까
악! '종이 컷'이다
Paper cut!
다른 애들한테도 말했니?
-Have you told anyone else?
-No, I don't want Monica to find out.
아니, 여기저기 알리면
모니카 귀에 들어가잖아
You told me.
나한텐 얘기했잖아
난 널 믿으니까
가까운 친구고
Because I trust you
and we're friends...
and you saw me looking
at ring brochures.
반지 카탈로그 볼 때
네가 불쑥 들어왔잖아
이래서 노크 안 하는 게 좋아
Once again, not knocking pays off.
-I wish you hadn't been on the toilet.
-Me too.
- 변기에만 안 앉아있으면
- 그러게
Let me see. Is there such a thing
as a Monica cut?
어디 봐, '모니카 컷' 같은 건
없니? 그거면 딱 걸려들 텐데
Because that would be you best bet.
- 얘들아
- 그래
-Want to go to the coffeehouse?
-Oh, all right.
챈들러, 커피 마시러 갈래?
- 그러자
- 커피하우스 좋지
잘됐다, 안 그래도
같이 가려고 했는데
We were just gonna see
if you wanted to go.
아냐, 우린 다른 데로 가거든
Well, we don't because
we got the other place.
How rude.
기가 막히는구만
Sorry. Want a bite?
미안, 한 입 먹어
The One With The Ring
So how are things going with Paul?
폴하고는 어떻게 돼가?
좋긴 한데
Good.
왠지 모르게 좀 답답해
Although, you know,
he's a private guy.
I wish I could get him to open up,
share some feelings.
서로 흉금을 털어놓고
감정을 공유하고 싶은데
그야 간단하지
You just have to think of him
as a jar of pickles that won't open.
뚜껑이 잘 안 열리는
피클 병이라고 생각해
I should run him under hot water
and bang his head against a table?
그럼 따뜻한 물에 담갔다가
머리를 테이블에 대고 칠까?
That's what you do when you want
to get the truth out of someone.
아니, 그건 자백 받을 때
쓰는 방법이고
- 나 왔어요
- 그래요
잘 봐
-Watch this.
-Okay.
그래
-Hey, Paul.
-Hi, Phoebe.
- 어서 오세요
- 안녕, 피비
요즘 어떻게 지내세요?
How are things going with you?
별 불만은 없죠
Can't complain.
- 어서
- 네
-Hey!
-Hi.
- 저런
- 이게 누구세요
-Great to..
-Ross, good to see you too.
- 여기서 뵙네요
- 나도 눈물나게 반갑구만
- 그럼 잘 있게
- 네, 가보세요
You take care.
피비, 전에 챈들러랑
왜 우릴 따돌렸는데?
What was the deal with you
and Chandler blowing us off before?
진짜 이상하지?
That was so weird, huh?
Why did you do it?
왜 그랬냐고?
I didn't do it. It was Chandler.
난 아냐, 챈들러가 그랬지
걔 너한테 화났어
He's mad at you.
-What? Why?
-Oh, please. I think you know why.
뭐? 왜?
알면서 뭘 또 그래
I can't think of anything.
전혀 모르겠어
넌 고생물학자잖아
좀더 깊이 파헤쳐봐
Come on. You're a paleontologist.
Dig a little deeper.
Is it because Joey and I didn't
invite him to that Knicks game?
잠깐, 몇 주 전 닉스 경기에
안 데려갔다고 그러나?
Is that something
he'd be mad at you for?
그 정도면 챈들러가 화를 낼까?
-I guess it could.
-Well, then I think that's it.
그럴 수도 있겠지
그럼 그게 정답이네
If he's angry, he shouldn't hide it.
I wish he'd just tell me the truth.
화난 걸 감추고 있으면 되나?
솔직히 얘기하고 풀어야지
그럼 따뜻한 물에 담갔다가
머리를 테이블에 대고 쳐봐
You should run him under hot water
and bang his head against the table.
Honey, I made a reservation
at China Garden. Is that okay?
'차이나가든'을 예약했는데
괜찮겠죠?
네, 전 좋아요
Yeah, that's great.
But first, talk to me.
Talk to me. Tell me about your day.
그 전에 얘기 좀 해봐요
오늘 하루 어땠어요?
It was fine.
괜찮았어요
Okay.
그랬군요
지금 무슨 생각하고 있어요?
What are you thinking right now?
그 옷이 당신한테 너무
잘 어울린다는 생각
That you are looking
really fine in that dress.
Yeah, that's great, Paul.
But, you know....
네, 그건 좋은데 말이죠...
I want to know what..
Wow, those are really great!
내가 알고 싶은 건...
와! 이거 끝내준다
이 강하고 과묵한 외모 속에
뭐가 있는지 궁금해요
I just want to know...
what is behind this strong,
silent exterior?
They say that still waters run deep,
and I want to swim in yours.
깊은 물은 소리가 없다던데
여기서 헤엄쳐보고 싶어요
Are you talking about having sex?
지금 섹스 얘기하는 거요?
No, Paul.
그게 아니라, 폴
I don't know anything about you.
Tell me about your childhood.
난 당신을 너무 몰라요
가령 당신의 어린시절
그 얘기를 해봐요
평범했지
Normal.
Then how about puberty? Come on!
That's always a painful time.
좋아요, 그럼 사춘기는요?
누구에게나 힘든 시간이니까
파자마파티에서 친구들이
Your friends have a slumber party
and stick your hand in warm water...
잠든 당신 손을 따뜻한 물에 넣어
침낭에다 오줌 싼 적 없어요?
while you sleep, so you pee
in your sleeping bag.
아뇨, 그런 적은 없는데
No, that never happened to me.
You're lucky you never
met that bitch, Sharon Majeski.
샤론 마제스키 같은 년을
안 만나서 다행이군요
어쨌든...
Anyway...
The rest of your life. Any regrets?
여태 살아오면서
후회 같은 건 없었어요?
Nope.
네
많은 걸 묻진 않을게요
뭐든 조금만 얘기해줘요
I'm not asking for a lot here.
Just give me something. Anything.
아무거나
좋아요
-Okay.
- 네
- 까짓 거 뭐
When I was 6 years old,
I wanted a Big Wheel.
난 6살 때
세발자전거를 갖고 싶었데
And instead, my parents
got me this little...
부모님은 콩콩 뛰는 조그만
플라스틱 닭을 사주셨어요
plastic chicken
that you hop around on.
It was embarrassing.
Kids made fun of me.
어찌나 창피하던지
동네 놀림감이 됐죠
정말 힘들었어요
That was a tough year.
That's great! See?
좋아요
그거 봐요, 벌써 당신을
잘 알게 된 느낌이에요
I already feel like I know you
a little better.
고마워요
자, 이제 식사하러 가요
가죠
Okay, come on.
Now we can go eat. Let's go!
It was horrible.
끔찍했어요
They called me "Chicken Boy."
날더러 '치킨 보이'랬어요
5학년 때 싸움을 했죠
사실 싸움도 아니었지만
In fifth grade, I got in a fight.
Well, not really.
Richard Danville bit me.
리처드 단빌이 내 코를
물어뜯어서 쓰러졌어요
I still have a little scar right here.
You can see it.
아직도 여기 흉터가 보이죠?
네
Yeah, yeah. I see the scar.
흉터가 있네요
I think this is really great that,
you know, you've shared your feelings.
저기...
폴, 속마음을 털어 놔줘서
너무 기뻐요, 잘한 거예요
It's really...
It's beautiful.
이젠 요기나 하는 게 어때요?
But what do you say we
go share some food?
지금은 못 먹겠어요
No, I couldn't eat now.
What are you talking about?
You love their Kung Pao chicken!
그게 무슨 소리예요
쿵 파오 치킨 좋아하잖아요
Chicken?
치킨?
치킨 보이!
-Chicken Boy!
-I'm sorry. I didn't mean to do that.
미안해요
그런 뜻이 아니었는데
없어
This is the nine millionth ring store,
and I can't find the perfect ring.
수십 군데를 돌아다녀도
완벽한 반지가 없다니
Ugly ring, ugly ring, ugly ring...
못생긴 반지, 못생긴 반지
못생긴 반지...
It's a beautiful selection.
아름다운 컬렉션입니다
좋아, 반지는 포기해라
So maybe you don't get her a ring.
Maybe you do something different.
다른 것도 좋잖아
가령 약혼 팔찌라든가
아니면 약혼 머리장식
An engagement bracelet
or an engagement tiara!
약혼 독립전쟁 소총도 있네
An engagement Revolutionary War musket!
널 데려온 게 천만다행이다
I'm so glad I picked you
to help me with this.
Imagine getting down on one knee...
무릎을 꿇고 이 근사한 무기를
모니카한테 넘겨주는 거야
and handing her this gorgeous
piece of weaponry?
I'll stick with the ring.
그냥 반지로 할래
This one's nice. I like it. Sir?
이거 좋다, 맘에 들어
여기요, 이 반지 좀 볼까요?
Kind sir, can I see this one?
이제 내가 나설 차례야
흥정은 내게 맡겨
This is why you brought me.
I know how to haggle.
넌 가만히 있으라고
-Let me handle this from here.
-Can I help you?
부르셨습니까?
네, 이 반지 좀 보여주세요
-I would like to see that ring.
-Or not. Whatever.
안 되면 할 수 없고
This ring is from the 1920s.
1920년대 물건입니다
1.5 캐럿 다이아몬드에
양쪽엔 사파이어가 박혀있죠
It's a one and a half carat diamond
with sapphires.
Sir, could I ask you...?
실례지만...
Could you hold out that ring
and ask me to marry you?
그 반지 들고 저한테
청혼 한번 해주실래요?
-Okay.
- 그러죠
- 네
Will you marry me?
결혼해주시겠어요?
Oh, my God, that's it!
That's the ring!
맙소사, 바로 이 반지야
-How much is it?
-I will handle this.
얼마죠?
챈들러, 내가 한다니까
How much is it?
이거 얼마예요?
$8600.
8,600달러입니다
10달러 드리죠
We will give you $10.
-Are you interested in this ring?
-Yes.
사긴 사실 건가요?
그럼요, 하지만
8천 달러밖에 없습니다
But I can only pay $8000.
-Okay. I can let it go for 8.
-We stand firm at $10.
8천까지는 해드리죠
10달러 이상은 안 돼요
-How would you like to pay?
-Credit card.
어떻게 지불하시겠습니까?
신용카드요
Oh, no! I lent my credit card
to Joey.
이런, 카드를 조이한테
맡기고 왔네
금방 다녀올게
넌 반지를 맡아 줘
I'll go get it.
You guard the ring.
알았어, 카드는 왜
조이한테 빌려줬어?
-Why did you give your credit card to Joey?
-To buy some Knicks tickets.
닉스 티켓 사라고 했더니
나만 쏙 빼놓고 갔잖아
Then the jerk didn't even invite me
to the game. But I'm over it. Whatever!
뭐 이젠 상관없어
Listen, I'm sorry about before.
아까는 죄송했어요
Do you have anything here for $10?
10달러짜리 물건은 없나요?
Yes. I have these two
rather beautiful...
네, 여기 아주 예쁜
5달러짜리 지폐 두 장
five-dollar bills.
I'll give you $1 for them.
1달러 드리죠
Remember how Chandler
and Phoebe blew us off yesterday?
어제 챈들러랑 피비가
우리 따돌린 거 기억나?
No.
아니
-Remember, you were eating pizza?
-Yeah.
피자 먹은 건 생각나냐?
- 그럼
- 좋아
Chandler's angry at us for not getting
him a ticket to that Knicks game.
닉스 게임 티켓 안 줬다고
챈들러가 삐진 것 같아
우리가 걔한테 티켓을 줘야 돼?
We were supposed to just get him one?
That guy's always mooching off of us.
그 자식 걸핏하면 우리
등쳐먹을 생각 뿐이야
그러게
Anyway, I still think we should
try to patch things up.
어쨌든 이 상황은 수습해야지
다음 닉스 경기 티켓 구해서
녀석을 데려가자
We could get tickets to another
game and invite him.
그거 좋은 생각이다
That's a great idea.
And I still have his credit card.
아직 챈들러의 신용카드가 있거든
여기
Here you go.
잠깐, 내가 계산할게
Hey, hey. I got this one.
Here you go.
여기요
Sometimes I just don't get Chandler.
가끔은 챈들러 녀석을
이해 못하겠어
항상 너 빼고 챈들러랑 나만
놀아도 넌 안 삐치잖아
We do stuff all the time without you,
and you don't get all upset.
-All the time?
-All the time.
항상?
항상이지
I'm sorry, it was rejected.
사용 중지라는데?
그럴 리가 있나요, 봐요
That's impossible. Let me see that.
내 거구나, 여기 있어요
This one's mine. Here you go.
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
내가 미친다 미쳐
-Still crying?
-Like a little girl.
아직도 우니?
계집애처럼
알아, 다 내 잘못이야
I know, I know. This is all my fault.
마음을 열어보려고 한 건데
I wanted him to open up.
I didn't know that
I was gonna unleash...
질질 짜면서 엉겨 붙는
응석받이 괴물을 깨웠어
this weepy, clingy,
moist monster!
I only know of two ways to shut
a man up. One of them is sex.
확실한 대처방법은 두 가진데
그 중 하나가 섹스야
-What's the other?
-Don't know. Never had to use it.
나머지 하나는?
나도 몰라, 다른 건
써본 적이 없거든
I'm just saying, if we're having sex,
he's not talking.
일단 섹스를 시작하면
챈들러는 입을 닫거든
맞아, 대신 네가 입을 열지
That's right. You're the talker.
Anyway, great idea.
어쨌든 좋은 생각이다
가게에 가서 휴지 좀
더 사온다고 했거든
I gotta buy him some more tissues.
-We have some here.
-No, you don't!
- 여기도 있는데
- 어허, 됐어
Okay. I'd also like
to try on the tiara.
됐어요
이 왕관도 한번 써볼게요
네, 좋아요
Oh, yeah. Okay.
What do you think? Too much?
어때요? 너무 과한가요?
A tad.
약간
알았어요
그럼 이 왕관은 다시 벗고
Take the tiara back...
아까 그 총 다시 줘 봐요
and let me hold the musket again.
Something's missing.
뭔지 모르게 허전한데...
Let me see the ring that
my friend picked out.
아까 제 친구가 골랐던
반지 좀 주세요
1920년대 프린세스 컷 반지요
-Where's the 1920s princess-cut ring?
-I just sold it to that gentleman.
방금 저 신사 분께 팔았어요
안 돼!
Oh, my God!
거기 서요
Wait, no!
엄마야! 난 몰라!
꺼내줘요! 당장!
Let me out! Now!
Rachel?
레이첼...
No.
아닌데요
-How are you, Paul?
-Okay.
잘 지내시죠?
그럼
Chandler...
챈들러
-did your dad ever hug you?
-No. Did he hug you?
자네 아버진 자넬 안아줬나?
아뇨, 선생님을 안던가요?
No! No.
그게 아니라...
It's just that my dad never did.
우리 아버진 날
안아주지 않았어
I miss my dad.
아버지가 그리워
You can see my dad in Vegas
kissing other dads.
우리 아버지는 라스베이거스에서
다른 아버지들이랑 키스를 하죠
-Hey, Chandler?
-Yeah?
- 이봐, 챈들러
- 네
Would you...?
날...
Would you hug me?
날 안아주겠나?
-I'm a little busy here, Paul.
-That's what my dad used to say.
전 지금 바쁜데요
우리 아버지도 늘 그렇게 말했어
Okay. A quick one.
Come on, hug it out.
좋아요, 이리 와요
안아줄게요
어허!
안았어요
There you go.
Okay.
좋아요
- 5초만 더
- 됐습니다
-Five more seconds..
-Okay!
- 야
- 조이!
-Joey!
-What? Hey, what..?
이건 또...
Hi. Paul, is it?
안녕하세요, 폴 맞죠?
-Do you have my credit card?
-Yeah. It's in my...
내 신용카드 있냐?
그래, 여기...
In my pocket.
내 주머니에
- 뒷주머니야
- 다행이다
-My back pocket!
-Thank God.
-I got tickets to the Knicks tonight.
-I can't go.
오늘밤 닉스 티켓 끊었다
난 못 가
가자, 재미있을 거야
너랑 나, 로스...
It'll be fun.
Me, you, Ross and
Paul, probably.
어쩌면 폴까지
Look, I don't have time for this, okay?
I gotta go.
이럴 시간 없어
나가봐야 돼
That was mean.
진짜 심하다
Yeah, I know.
그러게요
-Get in here.
-Yeah.
- 이리 와
- 네
Chandler, I found the perfect ring.
챈들러, 완벽한 반지를 찾았어
그것도 괜찮지만
난 아까 고른 게 좋아
I'm gonna go with
the one I picked first.
Oh, wake up. The one
you picked is gone. It's over!
네가 골랐던 건 없어
상황 종료야
What?
뭐?
Some guy bought it. I tried to stop
him, but they put me in jail!
어떤 남자가 사갔어, 미안해
막으려고 했는데
저 사람들이 날 감옥에 가뒀어
-They put you in jail?
-The little jail between the doors!
- 감옥에 가둬?
- 저 문에 있는 작은 감옥
-I asked you to guard the ring!
-I know. I'm sorry.
반지를 지켜달라고 했잖아
알아, 미안해
하지만 이 반지가 더 나아
모니카는 그 반지 못 봤잖아
But this ring is better. And Monica
never saw the other ring.
저 사람이 그 반지를 내밀며
청혼했을 때 아찔했다니까
Yeah, but when he proposed to me
with the ring, I got goosebumps.
-Maybe it was the guy.
-It was the ring!
- 남자라서 그랬겠지
- 반지 때문이었어
-Was he excited about the tickets?
-No! He blew us off!
어때, 챈들러가 좋아하든?
아니, 완전히 물먹었다
- 뭐야?
- 그러게
-What?
-I know.
I can't believe it.
말도 안 돼
Can I tell you something?
뭐 하나 알려줄까?
I'm a little mad at him now!
이젠 내가 녀석한테 화난다
Can I tell you something?
나도 하나 알려주리?
Me too!
동감이야
He didn't want to talk to us
about being angry.
녀석이 꽁해서 얘길 안 한다면
우리도 아예 말을 붙이지 말자
Maybe we don't talk to him at all!
-Freeze him out.
-Right!
- 왕따 작전
- 바로 그거야
- 거 괜찮다
- 그렇지? 본때를 보여주자
-I like it.
-We'll show him.
이제부턴 조이랑 로스가
단짝친구다
From now on, it's gonna be
Joey and Ross, best friends.
그렇지
We'll be the new Joey and Chandler.
제2의 조이와 챈들러야
What?
뭐?
그니까 네가 나보다
챈들러랑 친하다는 거야?
You think you and Chandler
were closer than me and Chandler?
어허, 화내지 마
Hey, don't get angry.
We turn on each other, he wins.
우리끼리 싸우면
놈이 이기는 거야
저 왔어요
Hi, I'm back.
할 얘기가 너무 많아요
여기 다 적어놨어요
I've written down more to tell you!
잘됐네요
Oh, that's great.
No, actually, that's...
아뇨, 사실...
That's great. That's really great.
정말 근사하네요
당신이 뭔가를 쓴다는 게...
You know, I gotta tell you, writing,
all that writing, it gets me...
절 너무...
It gets me kind of hot.
흥분시키네요
Wait, wait. Listen to this:
잠깐, 이걸 들어봐요
Know what I wanted to be at that age?
내가 이 나이 때 뭐가
되고 싶었는지 알아요?
연인?
A lover?
-A surfer.
-A surfer?
서퍼
서퍼요?
- 넘실대는 파도를 타고...
- 잠깐 기다려요
-I wanted to be one with the waves..
-Hold on.
잠깐만요, 어디 보자
여기가 좀더 편하겠네요
Let me just get
a little more comfortable here.
이거 봐라?
노출이 너무 심하죠?
Wait a second.
-This isn't too revealing, is it?
-No.
아뇨
Whatever happened to that little dude?
당시의 그 꼬마는...
So full of dreams.
꿈으로 가득했는데
I don't care about the little dude!
난 그 꼬마 관심 없어요
I can't! I cannot listen
to any more of this!
더 이상은 그런 얘기
듣고 싶지 않아요
그런 거 듣고 싶은 사람은
정신과의사밖에 없다구요
The only one who'd listen
is a mental health professional!
That's only because
they get $100 an hour!
그 사람들은 한 시간에
백 달러씩 버니까
Do you know how much money I could
have made listening to you? $2000!
난 당신 얘기 들으면서
얼마 번 줄 알아요?
2천 달러예요
Know when I figured that out?
While you were talking!
그걸 언제 계산했게요?
당신이 주절대는 동안
날 이렇게 몰아붙여도 되나?
I can't believe you're trying
to stifle me when 14 hours ago...
옛날에 우리 엄마가 그랬다고
14시간 전에 누누이 말했건만
we figured out that's what
my mother was trying to do!
I'm sorry.
미안해요, 몰아붙일
생각은 전혀 없었어요
I don't mean...
I didn't mean to stifle you.
This is all just
a little overwhelming.
하지만 이건 좀
감당하기 힘드네요
레이첼
맞아요, 미안해요
I'm so sorry.
I didn't mean to overwhelm you.
힘들게 하려는 건 아니었는데
일단 마음의 문이 열리니까
It's just that
when those gates open...
닫기가 무지 힘들군요
it's hard to close them.
But they are closed now. Believe me.
이젠 닫혔어요, 정말로
마음을 털어놔 줘서
정말 기뻐요
I'm so glad. I'm so glad you shared.
And I'm glad that you're done.
끝났다니까 더 기쁘구요
So what do you say we....
그럼 우리 이제...
나도 그러고 싶어요
I'd like that.
That was so good!
이거 너무 좋다
Oh, oh.
뭐해?
I can't believe you talked me into
this gumball-machine-looking ring.
풍선껌 자판기 같이 생긴
반지를 사다니 미치겠다
풍선껌 자판기 아냐
정말 예쁜 반지잖아
It's not a gumball-machine-looking ring.
It's a beautiful ring!
그렇지 않아
No, it's not.
When I looked at the other ring,
I could see Monica's face...
그 반지를 봤을 땐 모니카가
기뻐하는 모습이 그려졌어
분명히 승낙했을 텐데
and I could see her saying yes.
Looking at this, I only see a ring.
이건 그냥 반지밖에 안 보여
Unless I look at it really closely,
and then I can see my own eye.
가까이 들여다보면
내 눈이 보이거든
내 평생 가장 중요한 일이야
완벽하게 하고 싶어
This is the most important thing I'll
ever do. I want to make it perfect.
좋아, 반지를 되찾을
방법이 있을 거야
Maybe we could get
the other ring back.
그 남자가 어디서 청혼한다는
얘길 들었으니까 가서 바꾸자
I heard where
the guy was gonna propose.
-Maybe we could get him to trade rings.
-I can't do that.
말도 안 돼
You certainly can't give her
that stupid gumball ring.
그 풍선껌 반지로
청혼할 순 없잖아
-All right. Where was he going?
-Yeah, it's a restaurant...
그게 어디야?
무슨 레스토랑이었는데...
'레인보우' 뭐더라?
-The Rainbow something.
-Rainbow Room?
- '레인보우 룸'
- 아냐
Rainbow Grill?
- '레인보우 그릴'
- 아냐
Somewhere Over the...?
무지개 건너편 어디?
-L'Espace.
-Rainbow L'Espace!
- '르스파스'
- '레인보우 르스파스'
No, just L'Espace.
아냐, 그냥 '르스파스'
I'd love to know how you got
from rainbow to L'Espace.
어떻게 '레인보우'가
'르스파스'로 변하냐?
No, you wouldn't.
알 거 없어
You don't wanna get in here.
- 알면 복잡해져
- 그래
There he is.
저기 있다
아직 청혼은 안 했군
여자 손에 반지가 없어
He hasn't proposed yet.
She has no ring on.
너 대단하다, 나중에
범죄수사에 나서보자
Wow, you're good!
After this, we should solve crimes.
Okay. Go get him.
자, 가서 얘기해
알았어
Oh, okay.
실례합니다, 손님
와서 전화 받으시죠
Excuse me. Could you
come with me? You have a phone call.
- 누군데요?
- 회사라고 하더군요
-Who is it?
-It's your office.
회사의 누구죠?
-Do you know who at my office?
-John.
- 존...
- 존! 잘됐네
Oh, John! Great!
-There he is.
-Hi. Okay.
이 분이야
안녕하세요
일전에 보석상에서
선생께서 구입한 반지는
There was a mix-up at the store.
The ring you have was supposed
to be held for me.
제가 점찍어 둔 것이거든요
다시 찾아가야겠습니다
I'm gonna need to have that back.
더 비싸고 아름다운 이 반지와
교환하자는 뜻입니다
In exchange, I'm willing to trade you
this beautiful, more expensive ring.
Wow, I would trade.
와! 나라면 바꾸겠다
It is beautiful, but I'm gonna use
this one. Excuse me.
그것도 예쁘지만
전 이게 좋습니다
이만 실례하죠
이쪽은 제 약혼녀인데
그 반지를 너무 좋아해요
This is my fiancee,
and her heart was set on that ring.
Do you want to break her heart?
상심이 클 겁니다
Yeah. Do you want to break
a dying woman's heart?
네, 죽어 가는 여자의 마음을
아프게 하고 싶지는 않죠?
You're dying?
죽어간다구요?
네, 죽어갑니다
Yeah, she's dying...
of a cough, apparently.
심한 기침 때문에
죽기 전에 그 반지를
꼭 갖고 싶어요
It's my dying wish to have that ring.
If I'm not buried with it...
그 반지와 함께 묻히지 못하면
제 영혼은 구천을 떠돌며...
my spirit will wander
the netherworld..
그만하면 됐어, 자기야
That's enough!
글쎄요
Oh, I don't know.
-Let me see it.
-Great. Okay, here.
- 그 반지 좀 보죠
- 네, 여기 있습니다
좋습니다, 바꾸죠
-All right, I'll do it.
-Thank you.
정말 감사드립니다, 훌륭한
남자 분과 결혼하시겠군요
And you are about to marry
a wonderful man.
전 곧 죽을 여자랑 결혼합니다
Hey, I'm marrying a dead woman!
Guys?
얘들아?
I've got something important
to tell you.
중대발표가 있어
Guys?
얘들아?
I'm gonna ask Monica to marry me.
나 모니카한테 청혼할 거야
I think we gotta end the freeze-out.
왕따 작전 끝내야겠다
Wait. Is this for real?
그게 정말이야?
그럼, 이 반지 봐
Yeah. Check out the ring.
Oh, my God!
엄마야
So you two are really serious?
너희들 정말 심각하구나
Yeah, pretty much.
많이 심각하지
You're gonna get married?
네가 결혼을 한다고?
We're gonna be brothers-in-law!
Come here!
그럼 이제 사돈지간이네?
And we're gonna be friends again.
그리고 우린 계속
친구 먹는 거야
그래...
What?
뭐?
-Water under the bridge! Forget it!
-Okay.
- 아무렴 어때, 잊어버려
- 좋아
결정된 다음에 알려주려고
했는데 참을 수가 있어야지
I was gonna wait till it was official,
but I had to tell you guys.
You're my best friends.
너흰 둘도 없는 친구들이잖아
꿈만 같다
-I can't believe this.
-Me too.
그러게, 네 속셈이 뭔지
대화를 좀 해볼까 했는데
I was planning on having a conversation
with you about your intentions.
I think I'm gonna cry.
눈물이 다 나온다
Oh! No more crying!
제발 울지 마라
I just dumped one crybaby.
I'll dump you too.
방금 울보 하나 버렸는데
너도 차버릴까?
I'm gonna ask Monica to marry me.
나 모니카한테 청혼할 거야
어머나
Oh, my God!
세상에
Oh, Chandler!
You guys are gonna be so happy!
챈들러, 너희들 정말 잘살 거야
-I know.
-Where's all the tissues?!
그래야지
휴지 다 어디 갔어
-Check out the ring.
-Oh, nice. One and a half carat, easy.
반지 볼래?
좋다, 최소한 1.5캐럿이네
- 얘들아
- 피비
-Hey.
-Hey, Phoebe.
챈들러가 모니카한테
청혼할 거래
-He's gonna ask Monica to marry him.
-I helped pick out the ring.
알아, 나랑 같이 반지 골랐어
You told her before you told us?
우리한테 알리기 전에
피비한테 얘기한 거냐?
She walked in while I was looking at
brochures. You can understand that.
반지 카탈로그 보는데
불쑥 들어오잖아
그 정도는 이해하지?
Guys?
얘들아?
God, that ring Chandler picked out
was so beautiful.
챈들러가 고른 반지
정말 예쁘더라
넌 수백 개 샀으니까 잘 알겠지
You should know.
You've bought like a billion of them.
아, 내 고통을 할퀴는 유머라...
Humor based on my pain.
You know what's funny?
웃기지 않니?
Of all of your wives,
I'm the only one who never got a ring.
네 마누라들 중에서
나만 반지를 못 받았어
This a big issue for you?
그래서 크게 서운하냐?
No, but it would have been nice
to have a little memento...
그건 아니지만 우리 부부생활을
기념할 만한 물건이 있음 좋잖아
of our married time together.
Something other than the divorce papers
and the hangover.
이혼서류나 숙취 같은 거 말고
반지는 포기하는 게 좋겠다
Ross is obviously
not gonna get you a ring.
But ask for a musket.
Ask for a musket!
대신 총을 사달라고 해
When we were married,
do you know what I never got?
우리가 부부였을 때
나도 못 받은 게 있어
섹스
Sex.
Well, yeah. No ring, no sex.
Big surprise.
반지도 안 주고 섹스라니
꿈도 야무지셔라
Get me a musket and we'll talk.
총 사주면 내가 생각해볼게